在上一集里
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
卓天越之锤？
The Forge of Solus Prime.
别让我后悔今天的选择！
Do not ever make me regret which one of you I spared.
将太空桥指向塞博特恩！
Target the space bridge for Cybertron.
仅仅挥舞了几下锤子 砰的一下！
A few swings of that hammer, and bam.
环陆桥就变成太空桥了
Our ground bridge is now a space bridge.
威震天已经发现“终极之锁”在塞博特恩了
Megatron has discovered that the Omega lock is on Cybertron.
必须阻止威震天 不惜一切代价！
Megatron must be stopped, no matter the cost.
汽车人已经抢走了“终极之钥”
The Autobots have seized  the Omega keys.
我们已经找到“终极之锁”了
We have located the Omega lock.
汽车人 我建议你们把钥匙交给我
Autobots, I would suggest that you hand over those keys.
如果我们拒绝呢？
And if we refuse?
我们就可以看着他们一起…痛苦地死去！
We can all watch them instantly perish together.
这可不是我所期望的首次塞星之旅…
Not how I wanted to spend my first trip to Cybertron.
红蜘蛛！
Starscream.
小杰克 出来陪叔叔玩玩？
Jack, it's time to come out and play.
有种就杀了我
Go ahead.
汽车人愿意为拯救我的星球而牺牲
The Autobots were prepared to sacrifice themselves for my planet.
我也愿意以死相报！
I'll do the me for theirs.
我也是！死变态！
Me too, creepy.
或许该让他们得偿所愿？
Perhaps we should oblige them.
倘若我的抉择 葬送了汽车人在塞博特恩的未来
If my decision dooms the future of the Autobot cause on Cybertron
那也只能坦然接受
so be it.
但我决不会弃人类盟友于不顾
But I will never forsake our human allies.
现在 如果愿意的话
Now, if you please
“终极之钥”…
the Omega Keys.
一次换一个
One at a time.
你先来 大个子
You first, big boy.
回头这东西要是打不开 我就让你把钥匙咽下去！
If I don't get the girl, I'll make you eat this key.
甭客气
You're welcome.
去你渣的！
Get scrapped.
如果这个小子重要到连领导模块都值得托付
If this human was important enough to entrust with the Matrix of Leadership
那么他也值得两块钥匙
he's worth two Omega keys.
别耍花样！
No tricks.
交出钥匙…
The keys, if you please.
擎天柱 成功了吗？
Optimus, were you successful?
救护车？
Ratchet?
是琼・达比
It's Joan Darby.
你好吗？
How are you?
呃…我很忙 达比夫人
I'm... Eh... Busy, miss Darby.
我正亟待汽车人的消息
I am expecting urgent news from the Autobots.
哦…杰克和他们在一起吗？
Oh. Is Jack with them?
不 怎么了？
No. Why?
我一整天没见他了
I haven't seen him all day
打电话也不接
and he isn't returning my calls.
我一有他的消息就让他联系你
I will have Jack contact you immediately should I hear from him.
请你原谅 我必须保持通讯链畅通
Now, if you'll excuse me, I must keep the comm lines clear.
救护车？喂？
Ratchet? Hello?
现在 见证塞博特恩新时代的开启吧！
Now bear witness as a new era dawns on Cybertron.
看啊 霸天虎的纪元降临了！
Behold! The age of the Decepticons!
火种源在上…
By the Allspark.
- 哇哦！\N- 哇哦！
- Whoa.\N- Whoa.
瞬间恢复原状了…
Instant home makeover.
焕然一新呐！
Shiny.
你已得偿所愿 威震天
You have what you want, Megatron.
这场战争属于汽车人和霸天虎
This conflict is between Autobots and Decepticons.
让我送人类回地球
Allow me to return the humans to Earth.
哦…我不建议这样做
Oh, I wouldn't recommend it.
他们在这儿要安全得多
They'll be far safer here.
太空桥已锁定目标了吗？
Is the space bridge locked on target?
正如您指示的 威震天陛下
Per your instructions, Lord Megatron.
好极了
Excellent.
既然我能统治两个世界…
Why rule only one world
何必只满足一个？
when I could rule two?
不！
No.
嘿 我是杰克
Hey, it's Jack.
我正忙着拯救世界 暂时无法接听！
I can't answer 'cause I probably out saving the world right now.
擎天柱 你听到了吗？
Optimus, do you read?
一个出现在大气层的未知能量柱干扰了系统
An unknown energy spike in Earth's atmosphere is crashing all my systems.
千万告诉我这和终极之锁被激活有关…
Please tell me this is related to the activation of the Omega lock.
既然终极之锁可以让塞博特恩复苏
If the Omega lock can restore Cybertron
那用在地球上也一样 对吧？
it'll do the same to Earth, right?
不
No.
它会将你的星球数字化 以便于适应新的模块
It will cyber-form your planet in favor of its new matrix...
并随之毁灭所有地球生物
destroying all indigenous life in the process.
多么原始的力量啊！
Such raw power!
我该如何命名新的领地？
What should I call my new domain?
新卡隆？或是…“死”球？
New Kaon? Or perhaps "Gilded Earth".
不！
No!
别碰我们的星球！
Leave our planet alone!
擎天柱 你能听到吗？
Optimus, can you read?
救护车…请打开太空桥
Ratchet, please open a space bridge.
我猜…咱们得取消归乡派对了
I guess we should cancel the welcome-home party.
快去照看我们的主人
Attend to our master!
他需要医治！
He requires medical attention!
擎天柱！
Prime!
他放任塞博特恩死去沉沦 徒留躯壳 我要他付出代价！
He will pay for dooming Cybertron to remain a lifeless husk!
哈哈哈哈哈！
Hahaha...
他们可以逃走
They can run
但再也无家可归了！
but they can never again run home.
孩子们？
The children!
发生什么事了？
What happened?
你们到是说两句啊！
Somebody say something!
擎天柱…毁了终极之锁
Optimus destroyed the Omega lock.
什么？！
What?!
你干了…
You did...
我别无选择
What was necessary.
当时地球危在旦夕
There was no time for another prolonged battle
没时间从容作战了
not with Earth in imminent danger.
于是你毁掉了…全宇宙中\N唯一能让我们家园复苏的东西？
So you destroyed the only device in any universe capable of restoring our home?
擎天柱…那个我们还有用啊
Optimus, we needed that.
你当时不在场 大夫
You weren't there, Doc.
你没资格去评论战场上的决定
And it's not your place to second-guess a battlefield decision.
我当然有资格！
It most certainly is!
一定有其他办法的！
There had to be another way!
事情并非那么简单 救护车
I-It wasn't that simple, Ratchet.
威震天当时用终极之锁攻击地球！
Megatron was using the Omega lock to attack the Earth.
擎天柱拯救了我们的星球！
Optimus saved our planet.
那我们的星球呢？！
What about our planet?!
挥洒了无数的能量
All of our struggles and energon spilled
牺牲了无数的战友
countless sacrifices
到头来却一场空？
for nothing?!
木已成舟 多说无用
Right decision or wrong, what's done is done.
我们又有新麻烦了
And we have another problem here on this world.
虎子们把杰克 神子和拉夫牵扯进来 他们已经不择手段了
The Cons just changed the rules when they put Jack, Miko, and Raf into play.
擎天柱！
Prime!
五角大楼已进入了一级战备
The Pentagon's preparing to go Defcon 1.
我需要知道咱们到底遇上了什么麻烦！
I need to know what we're dealing with!
你指什么 福勒探员？
To what do you refer, Agent Fowler?
你应该去户外亲自看看
Maybe you should step outside and see for yourselves.
救护车 看好孩子们
Ratchet, watch the children.
威震天已经完成了数字化地球的第一阶段
Megatron has managed to accomplish the first phase of his cyber-forming of Earth...
建造他的堡垒
the construction of his fortress.
在贾斯帕 内华达？
In Jasper, nevada?
我不明白
I don't get it.
我都把小镇给疏散了
I've already had the town evacuated.
他们干嘛要建在这儿？
Why here?
因为霸天虎已经发现了我们基地的位置…
Because the Decepticons have discovered the location of our base.
如今 我们痛失了让塞博特恩复苏的机会
Our opportunity to revive Cybertron has been lost
一切皆因擎天柱的背叛！
due to the treachery of Optimus Prime!
但从这里 从新卡隆城的堡垒开始
But from our fortress of New Kaon
我们将征服这个世界！
we will instead seize control of this world!
霸天虎 变形 起飞！
Decepticons, transform and rise up!
我等这一天很久了！
I thought he'd never ask!
上吧 我的大军！
Come, my armada!
攻击！攻击！再攻击！
Attack! Attack! Attack!
汽车人 撤回基地！
Autobots, into the base!
福勒 你在做什么？
Fowler, what are you doing?
尽我的本职
My job, two-ton.
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
外面怎么了？
What is going on out there?
霸天虎正大举进攻贾斯帕
The Decepticons have invaded Jasper.
福勒似乎认为他能阻止他们！
And Fowler seems to think he can hold them off.
特工福勒呼叫防空指挥部
Special Agent Fowler to air-defense command.
我需要紧急战斗支援
I need immediate combat support.
快呀 防空指挥部！
Come on, air-defense command.
一箭三雕
I'll be triple-dipped.
擎天柱
Prime
增援部队到了！
reinforcements just arrived.
福勒探员 你们的军事力量不足以对抗…
Agent Fowler, your military cannot prevail against the...
你们不会以为我会让你们独自享乐吧？
You didn't think I was gonna let team Prime have all the fun, did you?
哈哈 是老千！
Haha. It's Jackie!
千斤顶！你是怎么…？
Wheeljack? But how did you...
循着奇怪的能量波动来的
I picked up a strange energy surge.
不介意哥们掺一脚吧
Hope you don't mind the company.
不 只是经过那些事情之后…
No. It's just that after everything... well...
咱们仍然是队友 大夫 永远都是
We're still on the same team, Doc. Always will be.
救护车 将所有的人 准备进行转移
Ratchet, prepare to bridge everyone out of here.
你要放弃基地？
We're abandoning the base?
基地已经沦陷了
The base is lost.
千斤顶和福勒只是在争取时间让我们撤离
Wheeljack and Agent Fowler can only buy us time to escape.
大黄蜂 拉斐尔
Bumblebee, Rafael
你们先走
you will depart first.
我们分头走？
You're splitting us up?
我们不该一起行动吗？
Shouldn't we stick together?
团结一心？
All for one and one for all?
我们只有分散开才能成功突围
We must disperse to avoid capture
在下次重聚并有能力发动反击之前
until we can regroup and launch a counterattack.
我们的首要目标是活下去
Survival is our only priority now.
想炸死我 你们还早一百…
The day I'm outflown by a bunch of toasters is the day I...
我们没时间了
We haven't much time.
琼？
Joan!
去死吧！
You're scrap.
看谁能来救你 雷霆救援队！
And that's how you wreck a Wrecker.
哈哈哈哈
Hahahahahaha.
你呢？
What about you?
我留下断后 确保没有霸天虎尾随
I will ensure that the Decepticons cannot follow.
我从没想过一切就这样结束了
I... never imagined it would end like this.
我也一样 老朋友
Neither did I, old friend.
不…
No...
这里就是他们的基地
This is the place, all right?
这里“曾”是他们的基地
This was the place.
团结一致 我们赢了
United we stand
一盘散沙 他们输了
divided they fall.